Well, the last 16-20 days were the most
stressful days in my
life because everything was normal. Then, suddenly, a major
health condition
was detected in my father
and as a result, we were admitted to the hospital for around 16 days and were recently
discharged. The point is,
how stressful it is.
These over-all situations are not just
emotional but also financially draining.
This particular situation is not just
ours, but
many cases have happened to
us. When I
looked at all these events, I
knew that health insurance was
important.  But its importance is so great that it happens especially in
cases like major health conditions.
I have witnessed it practically. In this
one case, I have learned a lot of things.
With respect to
finance and with respect to health
insurance. Health insurance is
offered by many companies today and there are many
star marks. We have to be very careful. If we want to
take health insurance, when we take Bikas, when we
opt for a policy, they tell
us a lot and
give us policies. But
when we make a claim, when we start
talking about such conditions, classes start talking about this along with
personal emergencies.  At
some point, additional pressure starts to be created on top of that pressure. So,
how can we effectively
select health insurance?
I will discuss the initial
level, what are the
pointers that should be included in it? I will
talk about all the pointers. Then, I will explain what health insurances are better for this year 2025
or give the best opportunities in the best way
with proper
pointers. I will explain it in
a little detail. The
video is very very important.
Watch the video till the end. You should understand the complete information.
So, let's get into the
subject. First of all,
I will talk about the importance of health
insurance, but it is not just the basics.
Inflation is the rise in the
prices of goods and services that we use regularly year after year.
In
fact, we can see that the
inflation in India is very high,
around 14-15% on average
year after year. The
prices of medicines and healthcare facilities are
increasing. In fact, as
Nitin Kamath recently
tweeted, most
Indians are just one medical bill away
from bankruptcy. Basically, if
you are admitted to a hospital
or have some major situation, then this is happening today.
You can see an example.  You can see here how much it costs for situations like bypass
surgery or heart valve
replacement that are normal according to our lifestyle. There
are definitely more than enough possibilities for billing. We
are admitted to the hospital in most of
the cases. And this kind of
drastic change in our lifestyle is something that
almost everyone already
knows and especially the younger generation.
Even 10-15 year old children are being
detected with major health conditions today.
We are
leading such a lifestyle. And this is one of the shocking
news.  Nearly 50% of the
medical expenses
in India are out of
pocket.
People are providing the money that is in their pocket till now. When it
comes to medical situations,
more than 50% of the people in India do not use insurance. Overall, we
see that our lifestyle may be the
food we eat, the
environment we live in, whether
we want it or not, also creates certain
health related issues in us. Even if
we are fitness
freaks, I say that we are full of fitness. But at the same
time,
anything can happen in any situation. Just
one week can change there.
Our recent one  According to experience, it is
better to prepare better than to get better than to get worse. Now we come to the main point.
Here is how to select a
medical or health insurance.
What
pointers should we pay attention to while
purchasing health insurance? The
first thing to consider is the claim
settlement ratio. Because there are many
companies
providing insurance. When you compare, the claim
settlement is very basic. If
they have 100 claims, then
how many percentage of them have been claimed in the claim policies? More than anything else, it is
better if they are giving more claims.
When you make a claim, you have to argue.  It may come up that it is not taken,
but after all this we define it
or it depends on it. Let's take a
look at different parameters here.
The second important parameter is the
hospital network. Basically, how many
networks are they covering?
Now, on the one hand, there
are 10,000, on the other hand, they cover 5,000 hospitals. If there is
a place near us, there may be metro cities, there may be
urban cities, we will go there and
check. Then suddenly,
you have to claim your absence and then
you have to pay money now.
We should not have such a situation. The more network we have, the
better.
We will take any insurance.
And the next product portfolio is basically the
availability of similar products for health insurance.
When you go, you will think that it is only one company. They
are offering 108 types of products and very
importantly, the needs of each person change from person to
person. It is
appropriate for us to select health insurance as per our needs. If you
are confused or need more information about this,
you can connect with a one-on-one call. Basically, there
is no spam. They will
directly contact you one-on-one and
understand your present situation and recommend you the best health insurance that suits you.
Their
website
also provides tools like guidance with respect to health insurance.
Like here you can see what
your current policy is related to health insurance.
Select your insurance here and select the policy and click on
check now.
You can check the details of your policy.
Compare
health policies. You can compare one health policy
to another.
Last
I will give an example about this.
And in this again, there may be things like section 80 DM.
At the same time, you need to
renew the policy. You have an
existing policy. You need to renew it.
You can also contact Dito Jim.
Discuss with you on a one-on-one call. Then,
discuss with you the better health insurance that suits you.
Personal.  So they recommend, there is no
spam game of any kind,
you will not be called repeatedly and you will not be bothered, those who are interested
can check the link description
and next, the point we need to
pay attention to is the track
record, how is their service, just like
Google, there are a lot of
reviews, different types of
reviews are provided online,
people have shared them publicly,
those reviews should also be
checked,
before taking any suitable policy, the
technical parameters like next, very very important
co-payment, etc. come,
ideally what happens now we
take a policy, we give 80%,
you have to give 20% at the time
of claim, and other conditions
are put there, the basis of this is there  They
define the price or vary the price.
Ideally, how do we select
health insurance? We
have four health insurance plans. Whichever one is
cheaper is better.
We have an intention there. But in
reality, it is very important to understand the things behind it.
Please do not go for cheap health insurance. Understand the
logic behind it. You can proceed.
Co-payment is one of the most important
parameters. 100% from their side. In a situation where health
insurance or health claim is
given, that company
or that policy should be there. This should be understood as the
appropriate next step.
Room rent restrictions are basic.
Now there are different types of
wards in hospitals.
We may have restrictions in any case, at least
a basic AC
room, we need support to get a settlement
or stay there.
This is also very important for us to check in the policy. In
some cases, you will have to pay
manually. If you have any
kind of stay,
then in fact, you should tell us.
Our recent bill is more than 35
to 40% of the bill, which is just for the stay. In fact, if you have stayed in the ICU,
you will save all that. If you have
stayed in the ICU, there are
possibilities that will be very costly.
We should check this properly. We should not have
any
kind of restrictions in this
matter. And the next
point is the waiting period. Now, some problems are being faced.  I already have
diabetes, I have
BP, in such cases,
these chronic diseases are
permanent, so there is an
expectation that ideally there is a
waiting period. Are you
paying the premium today? I already have an
illness like this,
but they do not cover diseases related to that illness.
Let's say there is a three-year waiting period. Let's
say you pay the premium for three years, then the
coverage
starts. So
what happens in some cases? I don't want to wait three years. I have to start
immediately. For example, let's say a
person has
diabetes.
I have a claim that I want to start immediately.
So there is an idea that
by paying an additional payment, an additional premium, that waiting
period can be reduced.
There are possibilities, we also need to
understand this. It is appropriate to ask them if you
are taking a policy.
What kind of
waiting period is there?
Are you ready for the waiting period or not? It is appropriate to know
how much additional payment you need to make and
reduce your waiting period. It is appropriate to come next year. Are
you hospitalized? It comes as pre-hospitalization or post-
hospitalization. It means that
a particular disease is detected
or there is a problem. It means
how long the pre-hospitalization lasts.
For example, let's say there is a 30-
day pre-hospitalization. It
covers the expenses of 30 days before hospitalization.
Hospitalization is
usually more than 100-120 days, up to that time, there are
policies that cover any follow-ups or related expenses.
Some policies
have reduced this particular period by giving a lower cost, so if it is more or less within that,
they will not cover it.
So it is also important to note that the next step is to get a suitable
policy, such as whether it offers cashless facility or not. Because now that we have gone to the hospital, we have to pay the first amount and then start the claim process.
Instead of doing all this, do
you have a hospital in some
city or a nearby city?
So, it is very important to check whether the hospital in that city has a
cashless facility or not, because
even if there is a problem at that time,
you will be hospitalized immediately. There is no waiting process and
you do not need to pay money initially.
Only if the cashless facility is activated under the network, such
policies should be taken only if the appropriate
next step is taken. Alternative
treatments should be covered or in fact, it
should be done as per the regulations. But in some cases, there are
some classes in this too. It is important to
understand this too. It may be
Ayurvedic or care.
Separately, whatever
expenses come up,
our
policy should provide a facility to cover those expenses. This is also important for us to
check. The next important thing is the
no claim bonus.
Some policies offer a lower
charge by giving this no claim bonus. For example, if
you have made any claim this year, then
you will either keep the
premium the same for the next year or
increase the coverage. If you have not made a claim, then some
health insurance, in fact, most
of the health insurance providers are
giving it as of today. But this is
very important for us to know. Because if
you have not made a claim, then you have already paid the
amount and have not made a claim.
So you should get additional benefits.
Some policies do not
give related benefits. If the price is kept low,
we should understand this. It is important that at least the
coverage is more. The
premium cost should
remain the same. Health insurance is also something
we should understand.
Restoration
benefit is very, very important.
This is especially important in families. Have you done this?
Now, it may be husband and wife
or the form may have been included. It is
called floater. In
simple words, we will see through an example. Let's imagine that
Nataraj and
Shalini, husband and wife, have a health insurance of five lakhs. Let's
say that Nataraj has some problem.
45 lakhs has already been spent on this.
Another  Let's say you have saved 50000.
Imagine next month,
Shalini has some major issue and she has
spent one or two lakhs. She needs to go to the hospital for that
one occasion. If there is no
restoration benefit in the policy, then
45 lakhs has already been
spent for that year. Only 50000 has
been saved. Whatever is left is one and a half
lakhs. You have to pay it from your pocket.
So when there is restoration
benefit, it is automatically
exhausted. Now, a premium of five lakhs is available.
Whatever benefit there was,
it is exhausted. If you restore it
and next time, there is no
need to pay any kind of issue. There will be
a little bit of premium extra. But
having restoration benefit is
very, very important and  The last thing to do is to buy the
price. Many people
leave the price at the first level. They
take whatever is less and
go for health insurance. But you should
check all the benefits. The
lowest price in the ID is now
500-1000. What do they give you? At
least 500. What kind of cheap
level is there? What kind of
health insurance major benefit is not provided there? As of
today, if you ask me, even if you spend at least
5 lakhs, it is very
very
important and in most of the cases
it is more than 1500-1200. This
kind of cost depends
on the policy. But make sure you only  Do
n't go and define the entire thing by looking at the price. As we have seen so far, the
basis of your family's conditions is to
define the price. Don't go and think about what
health insurance is, which is very cheap. Don't go and think about whether you have better
benefits.
And very importantly, if
you are cutting it continuously, you will get
more benefits.
Now, the
important part of the video, related to health insurance, is 2025, where we will
understand what better health insurance policies are, which provide better opportunities and better options.
Aditya said, "Care Supreme."  Birla
Active One Max
or a policy like this is
compared here.
What are the three policies? More than that, as you can see here, they
have a claim settlement ratio of more than 90%. No
co-payment classes. There is no need to pay any kind of co-
payment from your side.
These three
policies have extensive coverage. There may be no
room rent limits. There may be
alternative treatment, there may be day
care, there may be restoration benefits.
What are the benefits that you will get through these policies?
You can check the detailed comparison by going through the details of the overall policy. I have
provided the details here and very
importantly, if there are any confusions in it,
you should know the details personally.
You can book a call directly with the Detour team. There is no
spam of any kind. They
also
help with documentation. So, my personal
opinion is that I would have taken a
health
insurance policy from them. So, call them directly and explain
your situation and get
counseling. Only then will it be appropriate to take health insurance. Because in a
better way, you will have the
possibility to get a health insurance.
Over all, there may be documentation, there may be
selection, there may be renewal.
They will help you with all this and since it is a
brand supported by the most trusted brand, Zero,
we can easily process it.
There will be a link description with all the details.
You can then check.  You
can book by calling with the same theme.
Last but not the least health
insurance is not a
choice as of today. I am not going to give it to you. I am not that kind of age. Let's see
later. There is no such
opportunity. Having health insurance is very, very important. Even if
you already have some coverage in companies, then make sure that at least
one to five lakhs of
health insurance is covered. You should see whether
this is right for you and your family. On
its basis,
you should plan there. The most important thing is to have suitable
and very important cheap policies.
Don't just go and define it on the price. Compare and understand all the parameters and
put the star mark aside and make
decisions.  It is very
important to understand that health insurance varies from
person to person and situation to situation. The
basis of this is that you need to define it.
When selecting the right entire health insurance, we have
discussed it in detail. If you have any
confusion or doubts,
please let me know in the comments. If you
have any suggestions, please also let me know
in the comments. In the coming days,
I will
define the contents, be it finance or health, and I
hope that you will be enlightened in all matters. I am concluding this video here.
I will see you again in your next video.
Until then, Jai Hind.